Artem Anosov. Jarvis Consulting

I am a recent graduate from the University of Manitoba where I majored in Computer Science. Throughout my studies, I enjoyed learning software development and databases most. As for programming languages, Java is my favorite which is what I used in most assignments and projects, due to its OOP nature. Although I love learning, I also love implementing it. As a result, I was involved in different group projects in school, the biggest one was developing the website in a group of four people. It was very interesting and provided me with tons of valuable knowledge. During this phase of my life, I also learned more about my hobbies which include going to the gym, traveling, playing soccer, ping pong, and pool. Outside of my academic responsibilities, I also worked as a grocery/drugstore stock associate and a cashier at London Drugs. This opportunity, allowed me to improve my communicational and multitasking skills. In addition to that, it also taught me the importance of finding a work-life balance that I am now able to skillfully employ in my role and experiences here at Jarvis.

Skills

Proficient: Java, Bash, SQL, Agile/Scrum, Spring Boot, Mockito, JUnit, Maven

Competent: Spark/Scala, Hadoop, Hive, Google Cloud Platform

Familiar: Python, C++, C, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, PHP, Phaser, Amazon Web Services

Development Projects

Project source code: https://github.com/jarviscanada/jarvis data eng demo

- Cluster Monitor: Implemented a Cluster Monitor Agent which is an internal tool that collects hardware specifications of each server and monitors usage of resources by each of the servers. All of the information is stored in the RDBMS (PostgreSQL). It helps the infrastructure team to generate reports for future resource planning.
- Core Java Apps: Implemented Java Grep App which is used to find text patterns in all files of a directory and write lines that contain a given pattern into a file. Created a Twitter CLI App that works with Twitter API and is used to create, show, and delete tweets based on using HTTP requests. JDBC App creates a connection to the PostgreSQL database using JDBC. The database contains multiple tables that simulate a market with customers and salesmen. Each customer can have multiple orders which include some products. The app helps to find a customer order using the order id and print order details using SQL queries.
- SpringBoot App: Implemented a microservice that allows users to create their trader accounts and do the basic operations on the stock market (buy/sell stocks, check the latest quotes, check their portfolio). The project was implemented using SpringBoot, Maven, Mockito, and PostgreSQL. To use the app, a user can send HTTP requests to the server with the application running and receive responses in JSON format.
- Cloud & DevOps: In progress
- Hadoop: Provisioned a cluster that was created using Google Cloud platform for processing files using Hadoop components (YARN, HDFS, and MapReduce) and Hive. The CSV formatted file that had been stored locally was transferred to HDFS. HiveQL was used to create tables of different formats on top of the data. Different sorts of manipulations on the data were performed including SQL like queries to get the required information from the tables. This was done using Zeppelin as a notebook.
- Spark/Scala: Provisioned a cluster that was created using Google Cloud platform for storing data using HDFS and processing them with Spark (specifically RDDs and DataFrames). The data was transferred from a local machine to HDFS. Using Spark APIs different kinds of processing were done on the data (selecting, filtering, joining, window functions, etc.) based on the given tasks. Zeppelin was used as a notebook to run all the commands.

Professional Experiences

Software Developer, Jarvis, Toronto (2020-Present): Completing complex projects under the guidance of the company leaders on core big data technologies that include Cloud, DevOps, Java, Hadoop, and Spark. Responsible for performing the duties of Scrum master in the Agile-based team.

Stock/Cashier, London Drugs Ltd., Winnipeg (2017-2018): Completed a training program on communicational skill improvements and dealing with customers. Worked with a great team under the guidance of different supervisors. Responsible for providing great customer experience in the store and satisfaction with the provided services on a daily

basis. Responsible for making sure that shelves are full of products and have a desirable look. Promoted customer rewards program.

Education & Academic Projects

University of Manitoba (2014-2019), Bachelor of Science, Major in Computer Science

- Developer, Car Market REST API, 2019: Developed an API that simulates the car market operations in real life (list, remove, find, update). Technologies used: Java, Maven, PostgreSQL, JPA, JUnit, Mockito.
- Developer, Suzuki Android Platformer Game, 2019: Developed a multilevel game with bit graphics and sound effects for Android. Created the main character and set of his abilities (move, jump, throw). Created different game enemies with different patterns of behavior. Created multiple collectibles. Technologies used: Java, Android Studio.
- Developer, Airplanes Web Browser game, 2019: Developed a colorful, multilevel game with the ability to purchase upgrades in the game store. Created different types of enemies (including boss enemies) with different patterns of behavior and abilities. Developed levels for the game with different types of difficulty. Developed an economic system of the game. The game currency is stars that can be collected at each level and then used to purchase upgrades. Developed the game store to purchase upgrades. Technologies used: Phaser framework for JavaScript.
- Developer, Educational Website, 2018: Developed a website for educational purposes which teaches the basics of web development. Created articles that teach users on main web development tools HTML, CSS, JS. Each article provides image examples of code for better understanding. Constructed quizzes for assessing the knowledge of users. Technologies used: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Apache HTTP Server.
- Developer, Basic Chess Game 2015: Developed a chess game with three levels of difficulty. The game is played in the terminal. Created three patterns of game AI for the computer. Created difficulty levels based on the computer AI. Technologies used: Java.